Guide to the United Student Christian Council Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- USCC Committees and Commissions, Series III
  - Other Committees
    - Research Committee
      - Correspondence, 1947-1948, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 687)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Box 57, Folder 688)
      - Study on Student Centers on Campuses including Religious Centers for Student Work: a Yale Study: Chapel and Student Religious Centers in American Colleges by John Peter Thomas, 1946-1947 (Box 57, Folder 689)
    - Statement of Purpose Committee
      - Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 57, Folder 690)
      - Drafts, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 691)
      - Memos, 1951, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 692)
      - Minutes, 1951-1952 (Box 58, Folder 693)
      - Research Material: Other Organizations' Statement of Purpose Policies, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 694)
      - USCC Policy Documents including Report of Hearing Group II, circa 1952 (Box 58, Folder 695)
    - Student Veterans Emergency Committee
      - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 58, Folder 696)
      - Correspondence, re Fund Raising for a Chaplin at Champlain College, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 697)
      - Correspondence, re. Fund Raising for Projects at Farragut College, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 698)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 699)
      - Sampson College Project, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 700)
      - Shanks Village Protestant Inter Church Project, Camp Shanks, NY, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 701)
      - Surveys, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 702)
    - University Commission
      - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 58, Folder 702a)
    - Unmet Needs Committee
      - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 703)
      - Memos, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 704)
      - Minutes, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 705)
      - Papers and Reports re. Teaching Religion in Colleges, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 706)
      - YMCA Mailing List, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 707)
    - USCC Staff Committee on Ecumenical Ministry Among International Students
      - Consultation, The Ecumenical Mission of the Church and International Students, Ann Arbor, MI, 1956 (Box 59, Folder 708)
      - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 709)
      - Committee for Friendly Relations Among Foreign Students materials, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 710)
      - International Students in the U.S.A., 1957-1958 (Box 59, Folder 711)
      - Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 59, Folder 712)
    - Worship
      - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 59, Folder 713)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 714)
      - Papers, Ecumenicity in Worship by Roger Hazelton, The SCM: a Unique Form of Worshiping Community, and Study Paper on USCC Communion Policy, n.d., 1956 (Box 59, Folder 715)
- Conferences and Consultations, Series IV
  - USCC Conferences
    - USCC Annual Meeting/General Assembly
      - I Annual Meeting, Riverside Church, New York, NY, September 14-15, 1944
        - Articles of Operation and Minutes (Box 59, Folder 716)
      - II Annual Meeting, Wooster College, Wooster, OH, September 12-14, 1945
        - Briefing materials (Box 59, Folder 717)
        - Correspondence (Box 59, Folder 718)
        - Minutes includes newspaper clipping (Box 59, Folder 719)
        - Program material and reports (Box 59, Folder 720)
        - Questionnaire and answers re. history of USCC constituent organizations (Box 59, Folder 721)
      - III Annual Meeting, DeKoven Foundation, Racine, WI, October 22-26, 1946
        - Briefing materials (Box 59, Folder 722)
        - Correspondence re. Conference planning (Box 59, Folder 723)
        - Correspondence re. Delegates to conference including roster (Box 59, Folder 724)
        - Correspondence re. Location of Conference (Box 60, Folder 725)
        - Photograph of Conference Delegates (Box 60, Folder 726)
        - Program Planning (Box 60, Folder 727)
      - IV Annual Meeting, College Camp, Lake Geneva, WI, September 12-14, 1947
        - Conference Material (Box 60, Folder 728)
        - Correspondence, Delegates to Conference (Box 60, Folder 729)
        - Evaluations (Box 60, Folder 730)
        - Program Planning (Box 60, Folder 731)
      - V General Assembly, National Baptist Assembly Grounds, Green Lake, WI, September 11-16, 1948
        - Briefing Materials (Box 60, Folder 732)
        - Correspodence, re. Delegates to Conference (Box 60, Folder 733)
        - Correspondence, re. Delegates to Conference (Box 60, Folder 734)
        - Correspondence, re. Executive Committee (Box 60, Folder 735)
        - Correspondence, re. Program Planning (Box 60, Folder 736)
        - Evaluations (Box 60, Folder 737)
        - Literature Display (Box 61, Folder 738)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 61, Folder 739)
        - Nominations for USCC Committees (Box 61, Folder 740)
        - Resolutions (Box 61, Folder 741)
      - VI General Assembly, Bowling Green, Ohio, August 31-September 4, 1949
        - Briefing Materials (Box 61, Folder 742)
        - Correspondence, re. Delegates to Conference (Box 61, Folder 743)
        - Correspondence, re. Location of Conference (Box 61, Folder 744)
        - Correspondence, re. Program Planning (Box 61, Folder 745)
        - Documents Relating to Conference (Box 61, Folder 746)
      - VII General Assembly, Earlham College, Richmond, IN, September 2-10, 1950
        - Briefing Materials (Box 61, Folder 747)
        - Correspondence, Administration of Conference (Box 61, Folder 748)
        - Correspondence, Delegates to Conference (Box 62, Folder 749)
        - Correspondence, Leadership (Box 62, Folder 750)
        - Correspondence, Program Planning (Box 62, Folder 751)
        - Documents Relating to Conference (Box 62, Folder 752)
        - Documents and News Releases Relating to Conference (Box 62, Folder 753)
        - Evangelism Commission (Box 62, Folder 754)
        - Resolutions (Box 62, Folder 755)
        - Working Groups (Box 62, Folder 756)
      - VIII General Assembly, Earlham College, Richmond, IN, September 1-8, 1951
        - Briefing Materials (Box 62, Folder 757)
        - Correspondence, Administration of Conference (Box 62, Folder 758)
        - Correspondence, Bible Study and Worship (Box 63, Folder 759)
        - Correspondence, Delegates to Conference (Box 63, Folder 760)
        - Correspondence, Delegates to Conference (Box 63, Folder 761)
        - Correspondence, Leadership (Box 63, Folder 762)
        - Correspondence, Program Planning (Box 63, Folder 763)
        - Harry Smith's (Chairman of USCC) General Assembly file includes correspodence and reports (Box 63, Folder 764)
        - Reports to the General Committee (Box 63, Folder 765)
        - Summary of Evaluations (Box 63, Folder 766)
      - IX General Assembly, Western College for Women, Oxford, OH, September 6-13, 1952
        - Correspondence, re. Delegates to Conference (Box 63, Folder #767)
        - Correspondence, Orr, Bob (Box 63, Folder 768)
        - Correspondence, re. Program Planning (Box 63, Folder 769)
        - Documents Relating to Conference (removed from binder) (Box 64, Folder 770)
        - Documents Relating to Conference (removed from binder) (Box 64, Folder 771)
      - X General Assembly, Garrett Biblical Institute, Evanston, IL, September 5-12, 1953
        - Correspondence, re. Actions taken at Assembly and Resolutions (Box 64, Folder 772)
        - Documents Relating to Conference (removed from binder) (Box 64, Folder 773)
        - Documents Relating to Conference (removed from binder) including Herluf Jensen's Orientation Packet (Box 64, Folder 774)
        - Reports (Box 64, Folder 775)
      - XI General Assembly, Western College for Women, Oxford, OH, September 5-10, 1954
        - Correspondence, re. Delegates to Conference (Box 64, Folder 776)
        - Correspondence, re. Program Planning (Box 64, Folder 777)
        - Directory (Box 64, Folder 778)
        - Documents (Box 65, Folder 779)
        - Papers: Interior Life of the SCM by Andrew Yoggy and Our Student Christian Movement: Its Responsibility Toward Our Churches by Jacques Beaumont (Box 65, Folder 780)
        - Reports includes drafts (Box 65, Folder 781)
      - XII General Assembly, Heidelberg College, Tiffin, OH, September 3-10, 1955
        - Advance Registration Forms (Box 65, Folder 782)
        - Correspondence, Committee on Ecumenical Voluntary Service Projects, Committee on Nominations, Committee on Resolutions, and Committee on Social and Political Responsibility (Box 65, Folder 783)
        - Correspondence, Committee on Structure and Constitution, Committee on Study Program and Conference, and Committee on WSCF--International Student Affairs (Box 65, Folder 784)
        - Correspondence, re. Communion at the Conference (Box 65, Folder 785)
        - Correspondence, re. Delegates to Conference (Box 65, Folder 786)
        - Correspondence, Executives of Member Movements and Executive Committee (Box 65, Folder 787)
        - Correspondence, General Invitations--Observer Status (Box 65, Folder 788)
        - Correspondence, re. Location of conference (Box 65, Folder 789)
        - Correspondence, re. Member movement worship services (Box 65, Folder 790)
        - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (Box 65, Folder 791)
        - Correspondence, Speaker invitation and replies (Box 65, Folder 792)
        - Correspondence, Study group leaders and worship deacons (Box 65, Folder 793)
        - Delegation numbers and directory (Box 66, Folder 794)
        - Finances (Box 66, Folder 795)
        - Program planning (Box 66, Folder 796)
        - Reports, Committee on Evangelism in Colleges and Universities and Report of the Executive Secretary to the XII General Assembly (Box 66, Folder 797)
        - Thank You letters (Box 66, Folder 798)
      - XIII General Assembly, National Baptist Assembly Grounds, Green Lake, WI, September 5-11, 1956
        - Correspodence, re. Delegates to conference (Box 66, Folder 799)
        - Correspondence, re. Location of conference (Box 66, Folder 800)
        - Directory (Box 66, Folder 801)
        - Matters, Papers to be brought to the General Assembly (Box 66, Folder 802)
        - Orientation Packet (Box 66, Folder 803)
        - Reports to the General Assembly from various committees (Box 66, Folder 804)
      - XIV General Assembly, College of Wooster, Wooster, OH, September 5-11, 1957
        - Advance Registration (Box 67, Folder 805)
        - Circular Letters (Box 67, Folder 806)
        - Correspondence, Delegates from Member Movements to conference (Box 67, Folder 807)
        - Correspondence, re. Fraternal delegates or observers (Box 67, Folder 808)
        - Correspondence, re. International students (Box 67, Folder 809)
        - Correspondence, re. Leadership assignments (Box 67, Folder 810)
        - Correspondence, re. Leadership in General Assembly commissions (Box 67, Folder 811)
        - Correspondence, re. Location of conference (Box 67, Folder 812)
        - Correspondence, re. Miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 813)
        - Correspondence, re. Nominations Committee (Box 67, Folder 814)
        - Correspondence, re. Related Organizations (Box 67, Folder 815)
        - Correspondence, re. Resolution Committee (Box 67, Folder 816)
        - Housing at Conference (Box 67, Folder 817)
        - Material for XIV General Assembly minutes (Box 67, Folder 818)
        - New Releases re. XIV General Assembly (Box 67, Folder 819)
        - Orientation Packet (Herluf Jensen's) (Box 68, Folder 820)
        - Pre-Assembly applications (Box 68, Folder 821)
        - Preparation of reports (Box 68, Folder 822)
        - Programming (Box 68, Folder 823)
        - Reports (Box 68, Folder 824)
      - XV General Assembly, North Central College, Naperville, IL, September 5-11, 1958
        - Briefing materials (Box 68, Folder 825)
        - Commission III--NSCF Merger (Box 68, Folder 826)
        - Commission V--Christian Unity and the Socio-Political Task of the American Student Christian Movement (Box 68, Folder 827)
        - Correspondence, General (Box 68, Folder 828)
        - Correspondence, re. International Students and Invitations to Fraternal Delegates (Box 68, Folder 829)
        - Correspondence, re. Leadership at General Assembly (Box 68, Folder 830)
        - Correspondence, re. Location of Conference (Box 68, Folder 831)
        - Delegate rosters (Box 68, Folder 832)
        - Housing at conference (Box 68, Folder 833)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 69, Folder 834)
        - Newspaper clippings and news releases (Box 69, Folder 835)
        - Original copies of reports (Box 69, Folder 836)
        - Photographs, Herluf Jensen, Philippe Maury, Judy Hine, Irma M. Batoon, Reuben R. Batoon, and miscellaneous group shots (Box 69, Folder 837)
        - Program planning (Box 69, Folder 838)
        - Reports to the General Assembly (Box 69, Folder 839)
        - Worship at the General Assembly (Box 69, Folder 840)
    - Study conferences
      - Ecumenical Student Conference, University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS, December 27, 1948-January 1, 1949
        - Administrative Committee (Box 69, Folder 841)
        - Bible study (Box 69, Folder 842)
        - Book store (Box 69, Folder 843)
        - Briefing material (Box 69, Folder 844)
        - Conference report planning (Box 69, Folder 845)
        - Directory (Box 69, Folder 846)
        - Documents--Speeches, etc. (Box 69, Folder 847)
        - The Eclogue: Daily News Sheet of ESCON (Box 69, Folder 848)
        - ESCON follow up (Box 69, Folder 849)
        - Finances (Box 70, Folder 850)
        - Fireside group coordination (Box 70, Folder 851)
        - Fraternal and international delegates (Box 70, Folder 852)
        - General administration of conference (Box 70, Folder 853)
        - Leadership at conference (Box 70, Folder 854)
        - Local committee (Box 70, Folder 855)
        - Location of conference (Box 70, Folder 856)
        - Member movement meetings at conference (Box 70, Folder 857)
        - Mincon analysis reports (Box 70, Folder 858)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 70, Folder 859)
        - Personnel Committee (Box 70, Folder 860)
        - Program-Projects Committee (Box 70, Folder 861)
        - Publicity for conference (Box 70, Folder 862)
        - Quota numbers for delegates to conference (Box 70, Folder 863)
        - Recreation Committee (Box 71, Folder 864)
        - Registration (Box 71, Folder 865)
        - Registration (Box 71, Folder 866)
        - Requests for information (Box 71, Folder 867)
        - Speakers (Box 71, Folder 868)
        - Steering Committee (Box 71, Folder 869)
        - Sub Conference program planning (Box 71, Folder 870)
        - Thank You letters (Box 71, Folder 871)
        - Transportation Committee (Box 71, Folder 872)
        - Worship (Box 71, Folder 873)
      - National Quadrennial Study Conference: Morgan State College, Baltimore, MD; Park College, Parkville, MO; Stanford University, Stanford, CA, December 27, 1952-January 3, 1953
        - National Administration of Conference
          - Administrative Committee (Box 72, Folder 874)
          - Biographical Information for Study Guides (Box 72, Folder 875)
          - Briefing Material for Delegates (Box 72, Folder 876)
          - Circular Letters (Box 72, Folder 877)
          - Correspondence: re. Book Stores at Conference (Box 72, Folder 878)
          - Correspondence: Deschner, John to Nelson, J. Robert includes Discussion re. Extension of Fraternal Delegate Status to Bayard Rustin (Box 72, Folder 879)
          - Correspondence: re. Finances includes Ledger (Box 72, Folder 880)
          - Correspondence: General (Box 72, Folder 881)
          - Correspondence: re. Insurance (Box 72, Folder 882)
          - Correspondence: re. Leadership at Conferences (Box 72, Folder 883)
          - Correspondence: re. Location of Conferences (Box 72, Folder 884)
          - Correspondence: re. Publicity for the Conferences includes brochure (Box 72, Folder 885)
          - Correspondence: re. Quadrennial Conference Deficits (Box 72, Folder 886)
          - Correspondence: re. Quadrennial Conference Deficit Appeals (Box 72, Folder 887)
          - Correspondence: re. Speakers for Conferences (Box 72, Folder 888)
          - Correspodence: re. Study Guides (Box 72, Folder 889)
          - Program Planning Committee (Box 72, Folder 890)
          - Program Planning Material (John Deschner's notes included) (Box 73, Folder 891)
          - Program Planning Material (removed from binder belonging to J. Robert Nelson) (Box 73, Folder 892)
          - Program Planning Material (removed from binder belonging to J. Robert Nelson) (Box 73, Folder 893)
          - Quota Numbers for Delegates from Member Movements to Conferences (Box 73, Folder 894)
          - Quota Numbers for International Students (Box 73, Folder 895)
          - Regional Committees (Box 73, Folder 896)
          - Report: Summary Report of the 1952-3 Quadrennials (J. Robert Nelson's Report to the Executive Committee) (Box 73, Folder 897)
          - WSCF Promotion at Conferences (Box 73, Folder 898)
        - Eastern Conference: Morgan State College, Baltimore, MD
          - Correspondence: re. Administration of Eastern Conference (Box 73, Folder 899)
          - Correspondence: General (Box 73, Folder 900)
          - Correspondence: re. Location of Conference (Box 73, Folder #901)
          - Correspodence: re. Study Program Coordination (Box 73, Folder 902)
          - Correspondence: re. Worship at the Conference (Box 73, Folder 903)
          - Directory (Box 73, Folder 904)
          - Evaluations (Box 73, Folder 905)
          - Newspaper clippings (Box 73, Folder 906)
          - Eastern Planning Committee (Box 73, Folder 907)
        - Midwestern Conference: Park College, Parkville, MO
          - Correspondence Administrative Committee for Midwestern Conference (Box 74, Folder 908)
          - Correspondence re. Conference administration (Box 74, Folder 909)
          - Correspondence re. Location of conference (Box 74, Folder 910)
          - Correspondence re. Program planning (Box 74, Folder 911)
          - Midwestern Program Planning Committee (Box 74, Folder 912)
        - Western Conference: Stanford University, Stanford, CA
          - Address List (Box 74, Folder 913)
          - Correspondence re. Administration of conference (Box 74, Folder 914)
          - Correspondence re. Administration of conference (Box 74, Folder 915)
          - Correspondence re. Alexander Miller's travel arrangements (Box 74, Folder 916)
          - Correspondence re. Leadership at conference (Box 74, Folder 917)
          - Directory (Box 74, Folder 918)
          - Pre-Registration (Box 74, Folder 919)
          - Western Program Planning Committee (Box 74, Folder 920)
      - Ecumenical Student Workers Conference, College Camp, Lake Geneva, WI, August 16-22, 1953
        - Correspondence, Executives of member movements (Box 75, Folder 921)
        - Correspondence re. Location of conference (Box 75, Folder 922)
        - Correspondence re. Preplanning for conference (Box 75, Folder 923)
        - Correspondence re. Preplanning for conference (Box 75, Folder 924)
        - Correspondence re. Speakers (Box 75, Folder 925)
        - Program Planning Committee (Box 75, Folder 926)
        - Publicity Material (Box 75, Folder 927)
        - Regional ecumenical groups includes report on activities by state (Box 75, Folder 928)
        - Requests for publicity materials (Box 75, Folder 929)
      - USCC-WSCF Ecumenical Student Conference, National College, Evanston, IL, August 15-31, 1954
        - Correspondence, re. conference administration (Box 75, Folder 930)
        - Correspondence, Follow up (Box 75, Folder 931)
        - Minutes of the Planning Committee (Box 75, Folder 932)
        - Program material (Box 76, Folder 933)
        - Publicity for conference (Box 76, Folder 934)
        - Quotas (Box 76, Folder 935)
        - Reports (Box 76, Folder 935a)
        - Speakers for Conference I (Box 76, Folder 936)
        - Speakers for Conference II (Box 76, Folder 937)
        - Study Materials, World Council of Churches Second Assembly leaflets 1-6 re. Faith and Order, Evangelism, Social Questions, International Affairs, Intergroup Relations, and The Laity-The Christian (Box 76, Folder 938)
      - Conference on Christian Faith and Law, Episcopal Retreat Center, Whitinsville, MA, April 12-14, 1957
        - Correspondence, re. Conference planning (Box 78, Folder 960)
        - Papers including The Christian Lawyer as a Public Servant by William Ellis and Summary of a Statement of the Effect of Religious Principles on Lawyers' Ethical Problems by F.B. MacKinnon (Box 78, Folder 961)
        - Papers, The Christian Lawyer as a Churchman by William Stringfellow includes critiques (Box 78, Folder 962)
        - Publicity material including The Church Review vol. xvi, no. 5, April 1958 (Box 78, Folder 963)
      - Ecumenical Student Conference: Central Southwest, Oklahoma A&M, Stillwater, OK; Middle Atlantic States, Chatham College, Pittsburgh, PA; Midwest Region, Northern Illinois State University, DeKalb, IL; New England-New York State, Syracuse, New York; Pacific Northwest, Pacific Lutheran College, Parkland, WA; Pacific Southwest, University of Redlands, Redlands, CA; Southeastern, Davidson College, Davidson, NC, December 27, 1956-January 1, 1957
        - Binder containing memos, minutes, and promotional material for the southeastern conference (Box 76, Folder 939)
        - Correspondence, Central Southwest (Box 76, Folder 940)
        - Correspondence, Middle Atlantic (Box 76, Folder 941)
        - Correspondence, Midwest (Box 76, Folder 942)
        - Correspondence, New England-New York State (Box 76, Folder 943)
        - Correspondence, Pacific Northwest (Box 77, Folder 944)
        - Correspondence, Pacific Southwest (Box 77, Folder 945)
        - Correspondence, re. Program Planning (Box 77, Folder 946)
        - Correspondence, Southeastern (Box 77, Folder 947)
        - Directory, Middle Atlantic Conference (Box 77, Folder 948)
        - Evaluations (Box 77, Folder 949)
        - Memos (Box 77, Folder 950)
        - Orientation packet from the Southeastern Conference (Box 77, Folder 951)
        - Minutes, Central Southwest Planning Committee (Box 77, Folder 952)
        - Minutes, Middle Atlantic Planning Committee (Box 77, Folder 953)
        - Minutes, Midwest Planning Committee (Box 78, Folder 954)
        - Minutes, New England-New York State Planning Committee (Box 78, Folder 955)
        - Minutes, Pacific Northwest Planning Committee and Pacific Southwest Planning Committee (Box 78, Folder 956)
        - Minutes, Southeastern Planning Committee (Box 78, Folder 957)
        - Photographs from regional conferences (Box 78, Folder 958)
        - Promotional materials (Box 78, Folder 959)
      - Bible Study Leaders Conference, Grand View College, Des Moines, IA, June 14-22, 1958
        - Circular letters/documents (Box 78, Folder 964)
        - Directory (Box 78, Folder 965)
        - Working paper, Bible Study and Witness on a University Campus by Reverend Hal Leiper includes rough draft (Box 78, Folder 966)
      - Conference on International Political Questions, North Central College, Naperville, IL, September 2-5, 1958
        - Ecumenical Leadership Laboratory, North Central College, Naperville, IL, September 2-5, 1958
          - Circular letter and registration forms (Box 78, Folder 969)
          - Correspondence (Box 78, Folder 967)
          - Registration forms (Box 78, Folder 968)
      - Conference on Christian Faith and Law, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, September 7-10, 1958
        - Biographical information on speakers includes photographs (Box 79, Folder 970)
        - Correspondence, General (Box 79, Folder 971)
        - Correspondence, Stringfellow, William (Box 79, Folder 972)
        - Minutes, Planning Committee (Box 79, Folder 973)